<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <properties>
    <title>DiffReport Task</title>
    <author email="sstafford@modeln.com">Shawn Stafford</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="DiffReport">
      <p>
        Compares the differences between two Jar files and generates an 
        HTML report of the files which have been added, deleted, or modified 
        between the two versions of the Jar file.  The tool uses the Jar CRC 
        checksum combined with textual/bytecode diff to determine whether 
        files from two different Jar files have changed.  If the files have 
        changed, the files will be extracted and a textual diff will be performed
        to highlight the changes.  In the case of binary class files, the classes
        will be extracted and disassembled using the <tt>javap</tt> command.  The
        disassembled code will be compared to determine which methods have changed.
      </p>

      <!-- ================================================================= -->
      <!-- Parameters                                                        -->
      <!-- ================================================================= -->
      <subsection name="Parameters">
<table border="1" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="0" width="100%">
  <tr>
    <td valign="top" width="15%"><b>Attribute</b></td>
    <td valign="top" width="80%"><b>Description</b></td>
    <td align="center" valign="top" width="5%"><b>Required</b></td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td valign="top">old</td>
    <td valign="top">Path to the original version of the Jar file</td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">Yes</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td valign="top">new</td>
    <td valign="top">Path to the updated version of the Jar file</td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">Yes</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td valign="top">reportdir</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Output directory where the HTML report files will be written.
      If a report directory is not specified, a summary of the differences
      will be printed to <tt>stdout</tt>.  When specified, this directory
      must exist and be a valid, writable directory.
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td valign="top">propfile</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Properties file where file counts will be written.
      The properties are count.toal, count.unchanged, count.added, count.deleted,
      and count.modified.  Default is <tt>${reportdir}/summary.properties</tt></td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td valign="top">maxlines</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Maximum number of lines in a single text file that will be processed 
      during a diff operation.  The default is <tt>10000</tt> lines.  
      If a class file's bytecode exceeds this value, the diff status will be determined by CRC checksum only.
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td valign="top">saveAdded</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Save a copy of each file that exists in the new version of the 
      file but not the old version.  The generated report will contain
      a link to the file.  Default is <tt>false</tt>.
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td valign="top">saveDeleted</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Save a copy of each file that exists in the old version of the
      file but not the new version.  The generated report will contain
      a link to the file.  Default is <tt>false</tt>.
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td valign="top">saveUnchanged</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Save a copy of each file that exists in the old version of the
      file and the new version but has no changes.  The generated report will contain
      a link to the file.  Default is <tt>false</tt>.
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td valign="top">saveModified</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Save a copy of the old and new version of the file when performing
      a diff.  The generated report will contain links to the old and
      new files.  Default is <tt>false</tt>.
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td valign="top">showDiffs</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Include links to the textual diff in the HTML report.
      The default is <tt>true</tt>. 
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td valign="top">showAdded</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Include 'added' files in the HTML report.  Files are considered 'added'
      if the file exists in the <tt>new</tt> Jar file but does not exist in
      the <tt>old</tt> Jar file.  The default is <tt>true</tt>. 
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td valign="top">showDeleted</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Include 'deleted' files in the HTML report.  Files are considered 'deleted'
      if the file exists in the <tt>old</tt> Jar file but does not exist in
      the <tt>new</tt> Jar file.  The default is <tt>true</tt>.
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td valign="top">showModified</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Include 'modified' files in the HTML report.  Files are considered 'modified'
      if the file exists in the <tt>old</tt> Jar file and the <tt>new</tt> Jar file
      but the CRC values for each file do not match.  The default is <tt>true</tt>.
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td valign="top">showBytecode</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Include dissassembled Java bytecode when performing a diff of Java class files. 
      Including bytecode can increase the size of the text files being compared,
      which may cause the files to exceed the <tt>maxlines</tt> limitation.  If
      this attribute is set to <tt>true</tt>, the <tt>disassembler</tt> attribute
      must reference a valid <tt>javap</tt> executable.  The default is <tt>false</tt>.
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td valign="top">disassembler</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Path to the <tt>javap</tt> executable distributed with the JDK.
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td valign="top">alwaysReport</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Always generate index.html under the reportdir even when theres are no differences to show.
      When set to false, index.html only appears when there are differences to be reported.  
      The default is <tt>true</tt>
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td valign="top">verbose</td>
    <td valign="top">
      Print a line of output to <tt>stdout</tt> for each file which requires 
      a diff.  The default is <tt>false</tt>
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center">No</td>
  </tr>


</table>

      </subsection>


      <!-- ================================================================= -->
      <!-- Nested Elements                                                   -->
      <!-- ================================================================= -->
      <subsection name="Nested Elements">

        <subsection name="PatternSet">
          PatternSets can be used to include or exclude files from the report processing.
          If no pattern sets are specified, all files will be analyzed.  
          If a pattern set is specified, all files are assumed to be excluded
          unless explicitly included by an <tt>include</tt> pattern.  See the Ant
          <a href="http://ant.apache.org/manual/CoreTypes/patternset.html">PatternSets</a>
          documentation for additional information about how to use the <tt>patternset</tt>
          tags.
        </subsection>

      </subsection>


      <!-- ================================================================= -->
      <!-- Examples                                                          -->
      <!-- ================================================================= -->
      <subsection name="Examples">
        <b>Compare the entire contents of two jar files</b>
<source>
  &lt;diffreport old=&quot;myjar-v5.7.jar&quot;
              new=&quot;myjar-v5.8.jar&quot;
              verbose=&quot;true&quot;
              reportdir=&quot;/var/tmp/report&quot;/&gt;
</source>


        <b>Compare only class and property files, exluding test files</b>
<source>
  &lt;diffreport old=&quot;myjar-v5.7.jar&quot;
              new=&quot;myjar-v5.8.jar&quot;
              verbose=&quot;true&quot;
              showBytecode=&quot;true&quot;
              reportdir=&quot;/var/tmp/report&quot;
              disassembler=&quot;/opt/java/bin/javap&quot;&gt;
    &lt;patternset&gt;
      &lt;include name="**/*.class"/&gt;
      &lt;include name="**/*.properties"/&gt;
      &lt;exclude name="**/test/**/*"/&gt;
    &lt;/patternset&gt;
  &lt;/diffreport&gt;
</source>

      </subsection>

    </section>

  </body>

</document>

